rimowa.de 2018-09-02

# Privacy Policy Rimowa

## A. Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

for the RIMOWA website June 2018

Thank you for visiting this website. Ensuring data protection and data security for our customers and users is a top priority for us. This privacy policy explains what information is collected when you visit and use this website and how this information is processed. If you would like to read the whole notice in context or would like to print it, please click here.

The website [https://www.rimowa.com](https://www.rimowa.com/) (also the "Site") is operated by RIMOWA international, having its registered office at Richard-Byrd-Str. 13, 50829 Cologne, Germany (“RIMOWA”) (email address: [hello@rimowa.com](mailto:hello@rimowa.com)), in its capacity as data controller for the purposes of applicable data protection laws and regulations.

##  2\. GENERAL INFORMATION

Protecting the personal data of users and customers is something we take very seriously and we comply with the applicable data protection law provisions. We only collect, process and use your personal data if a statutory provision allows us to do so or if you have granted your consent to this collection, processing and use. The same applies to the processing and use of personal data for advertising and marketing purposes. We can also collect information on this website that does not, in itself, allow us to draw any direct conclusions as to your identity. In certain cases, however – particularly if it is combined with other data – this information can constitute “personal data” within the meaning of the data protection laws. In addition, we can also use this website to record information that does not allow us to identify you either directly or indirectly; this applies, by way of example, to summarised information on all users of this website.

We use our privacy policy to explain, in particular,

\- what information we collect in connection with the use of this website and the functions it offers (e.g. placing an online order via this website) and how we process and use this information and

\- what information we collect in connection with visits to this website and how we process and use this information.

## 3\. DATA PROCESSED, LEGAL BASIS AND PURPOSES OF THE PROCESSING

### 3.1 Overview

Depending on the services provided by our website and used by you, your choices and the configuration of your device (with respect in particular to cookies and other trackers), personal data concerning you (your "Data") collected and processed by RIMOWA mainly include: Your family name, first name, title, e-mail address, postal address and telephone number, your bank account details for the purposes of online sales, your billing and delivery address, information on the mode of payment, your past purchases, your preferences and interests, as well as your connection logs. For each activity using your Data, we will establish an appropriate lawful basis. Therefore, Data shall be collected either with your express consent, or where necessary to fulfil your orders (performance of a contract), for the pursuance of our legitimate interests when the processing is required for the management of our (the data controller's) daily business activities, or for compliance with our legal obligations. The lawful bases we rely upon for key activities in relation to this website are identified in sections 3.2 to 3.6 below.

Your Data shall be collected for the following purposes:

\- to answer your questions sent via e-mail, contact forms and chats

\- to enable you to create a "MyRIMOWA" personal space or guest account (customer account) and thereby purchase our products online;

\- to manage any purchase orders that you may place online and their delivery as well as the applicable warranties;

\- register your products online, to get access to additional services

\- to provide you with a localised service – e.g. to find your nearest store or point of contact

\- to ensure the security of your online transactions, to prevent fraud and payment defaults (see our [Terms & Conditions](https://www.rimowa.com/de/en/customer-service/terms-%26-conditions/terms.html) for more details);

\- to manage and optimise the customer relationship as described in further detail in sections 3.2 to 3.6 below;

\- unless you object as indicated in the section below "Your rights" respectively in our Cookie Policy to better understand your preferences by analysing your behavior on our website and offer you products or services more in line with your interests;

\- subject to your consent: to send you information about our offers, news and events (newsletters, invitations and other publications);

\- to carry out statistical analysis regarding how this website is used (e.g. number of hits, duration of visits etc.) and of customer order behaviour. The Data that is indispensable for us to fulfil the purposes that are described above is marked with an asterisk on the various pages of the website. Should you not fill in these mandatory fields, we may not be able to process your requests and/or to provide you the requested products and services. Other Data is purely optional and allow us to know you better and to improve our communications and services accordingly. Further information on purposes and legal basis for specific processing scenarios can be found below.

### 3.2 Registration and customer account ("MyRIMOWA")

This website gives you the opportunity to register and create a customer account ("My-RIMOWA"). If you create a customer account, you will automatically be allocated a personal RIMOWA number ("MyRIMOWA ID") which is linked to the e-mail address you have provided. You can use your e-mail address for various RIMOWA processes and procedures (e.g. placing an online order). This is why you can also create a customer account independently of a specific online order. In order to create the customer account, we collect the data indicated in the corresponding registration form, in particular your title, first name and family name, postal address and e-mail address, as well as a password that you select yourself (“Master Data”). The mandatory fields in the registration form must have been completed in order to register and create a customer account. When we confirm your registration, we will allocate you a personal MyRIMOWA ID under which we will store your Master Data in our customer database. If you use your MyRIMOWA ID and your customer account for an online order or to use a further service, we will save the data collected in connection with the online order/use of the further service under your MyRIMOWA ID. We can process and use the data stored under your MyRIMOWA account to respond to enquiries about or requests for customer support, for example if you pose a question about registration, about your user account or other functions of your MyRIMOWA account to us, an affiliated company, a RIMOWA retailer or another customer support provider (customer support partner). 

We may grant customer support partners limited access to the data stored on our customer database as regards your MyRIMOWA account for this purpose, in compliance with data protection regulations (and usually within the scope of a contract stipulating said services). When you pose a request to us or a customer support partner, the content of this request is stored under your MyRIMOWA account. This personal information is used solely for handling your enquiry. 

The legal basis of any processing of your Master Data described in this section is performance of a contract.

We can also give you the opportunity, outside of this website, to register for further services using your MyRIMOWA ID and your login details for the customer account. In this case, your Master Data will also be used for the further service in question. We will provide you with separate information on the handling of your personal data in connection with the relevant further service.

### 3.3 Orders

You can place an online order on this website even without registering and creating a customer account ("Guest Order"). In this case, too, we need the data that is relevant to the order (in particular your first name and family name, billing and delivery address, information on the mode of payment and the corresponding payment details) and that you have to enter during the order process. The mandatory fields in the registration form must have been completed in order to place a Guest Order. We save the information that is collected and arises in connection with a Guest Order in our order data-base in order to process the online order and then to fulfil statutory retention obligations. 

If you place an order (on this website, by phone or in a store) using your MyRIMOWA ID and your customer account, we will save the information that is collected and arises in connection with the order under your MyRIMOWA ID in our customer database; this is also done in order to manage any purchase orders and their delivery as well as the applicable warranties. The legal basis of any processing of your personal data described in this section is performance of a contract and compliance with legal obligations (for example, our obligations under consumer protection law). 

### 3.4 Functions on this Website

On this website, we can offer you further optional functions for which personal data or other information has to be collected, e.g. if you participate in a survey on this website or send us questions or feedback. We will only collect, process and use such data and information to the extent that is required for the function in question (e.g. to answer your question or process your feedback). Some of this processing is necessary for taking steps at your request to enter into a contract with you. Additional processing is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests pursued by RIMOWA: We have a legitimate interest in improving our services as well as our website itself and in carrying out, inter alia, surveys in this regard. Such legitimate interest of RIMOWA is appropriately balanced with the interests of the users within the limitations abovementioned.

### 3.5 Direct Marketing without your consent

In certain cases, sending you direct advertising without your explicit consent is permissible by law. This may, for example, relate to the use of an e-mail address that we have received in connection with the sale of goods or services. In the latter case, we will draw your attention to this possibility and to your right to object when we collect the e-mail address. In all cases, you have an absolute right to prevent (i.e., opt-out of) direct marketing at any time.

The processing of your personal data described in this section is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests pursued by RIMOWA. We have a legitimate interest in direct marketing as long as we comply with the legal requirements for marketing (e.g., requirements for electronic marketing communications).

### 3.6 Connection logs

We record every time this website is visited and every time a file stored on this website is accessed. This pseudonymous information is saved for internal system-related and statistical purposes as well as security reasons. The information recorded includes the name of the file accessed, the date and time of access, the volume of data transmitted, notification regarding successful access, information on the web browser used, the requesting domain and the IP address of the requesting computer. The processing of your personal data described in this section is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests pursued by RIMOWA: We have a legitimate interest in saving connection logs for the purposes of determining disruptions and for security reasons (e.g., to investigate attack attempts) and in order to learn more about how our website is used. Such legitimate interest of RIMOWA is appropriately balanced with the interests of the users within the limitations abovementioned.

### 3.7 Cookies

In order to make our website as user-friendly as possible, we – like many other companies – use “cookies”.

Cookies are small text files that are sent when visiting an internet page and are stored in a user’s browser. In case the respective internet page is accessed again, the user’s browser sends back the content of the cookies and, thus, allows for the recognition of the user. 

This means, for example, that, if you are a registered user of this website, you do not need to log in again every time you visit the website. Users of our website use various different browsers and different computers. In order to make your visit to this website as pleasant as possible with the technology you are using, we collect information on the browser type you are using (e.g. Internet Explorer, Chrome, Firefox, Mozilla or Opera) and the operating system (e.g. Windows or MacOS), the domain name of your Internet provider, as well as the width and height of the browser window, the screen resolution and the colour depth. We also use cookies to analyse the use of our offering, to target in order to be able to make interesting information available to you and to ensure the functionality of our website. Most of the cookies we use are “session cookies” that are deleted when you end your browser session. You can find further information on the various types and the use of cookies and on how to deactivate them in our Cookie Policy.

Typically cookies do not collect personal data but may be used to create a user profile. In this case, you will be informed about this below. 

### 3.8 Website Analysis 

We use analysis services on this website to allow us to record information on the use of this website (e.g. pages or sections that are particularly popular) and to constantly improve our offering. 

The processing of your personal data described in this section is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests pursued by RIMOWA: We have a legitimate interest in collecting statistical information about the usage of our website in order to improve our offering. 

#### 3.8.1 Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis services offered by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California, 94043 USA (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies. The information on your use of the website collected by the cookie is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA (a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union), where it is saved. As an IP anonymity function is activated on this website, Google will shorten your IP address in member states of the European Union or other contracting states of the agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Google will use the information generated using the cookie on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports on website activities, and provide us with other services associated with the website and Internet use. The IP address transmitted by your browser to Google Analytics will not be linked to other Google data. 

You can set your browser software to prevent cookies from being saved. Please note, however, that if you do so, you might not be able to use all of the functions offered by this website. You can also prevent Google from storing the data generated by the cookie relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in that is available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

#### 3.8.2 Hotjar

This website uses Hotjar, a web analysis services offered by Hotjar Ltd., 3 Lyons Range, 20 Bisazza Street, Sliema SLM 1640, Malta (“Hotjar”). This service records, on an anonymous basis, interactions between individual visitors to the website, who are selected at random, and the website itself. This results in a log showing, for example, mouse movements and clicks, the purpose being to identify potential for improving the website. Hotjar also uses cookies that are saved on your computer to analyse your use of the website. In order to prevent information being directly linked to a particular individual, IP ad-dresses are rendered anonymous before they are saved and processed further. Information on operating systems, browsers, incoming and outgoing links, geographical origin and the resolution and type of device is also analysed for statistical purposes. This information does not relate to specific individuals and is not disseminated to third parties either by us or by Hotjar. If you want to stop Hotjar from collecting data, you can find further information [here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

#### 3.8.3 Klaviyo

This website uses Klaviyo. Klaviyo is a multifunctional email platform that is being used for order related communication as well as the sending of newsletters. It will also generate statistical information that might be used to improve our email communication. The Klaviyo tool will be generating statistical information if you have given your consent to receiving the RIMOWA newsletter. Klaviyo is provided by Klaviyo Inc, Boston, USA and information is stored in the USA, a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union). You can read more about their privacy policy here: [here](https://www.klaviyo.com/privacy/policy). If you want to stop this tool from collecting data, you can opt-out [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/).

### 3.9 Tracking and Facebook Pixel 

We use tracking tools including the Facebook Pixel on this website to better understand your preferences by analysing your behavior on our website and offer you products or services more in line with your interests. 

The processing of your personal data described in this section is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests pursued by RIMOWA: We have a legitimate interest in efficient online marketing as long as you don’t object.

#### 3.9.1 Doubleclick Floodlight Tags

This website uses Doubleclick Floodlight Tags (more details [here)](https://support.google.com/ds/answer/2404957?hl=de), a tool provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California, 94043 USA (“Google”). DoubleClick uses cookies to improve advertising. Some common applications are to target advertising based on what’s relevant to a user, to improve reporting on campaign performance, and to avoid showing ads the user has already seen.

DoubleClick sends a cookie to the browser after any impression, click, or other activity resulting in a call to a Google server in the USA, a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union. If the browser accepts the cookie, the cookie is stored in the browser.

Most commonly, DoubleClick sends a cookie to the browser when a user visits a page that shows DoubleClick ads. Pages with DoubleClick ads include ad tags that instruct browsers to request ad content from our servers. When the server delivers the ad content, it also sends a cookie. But a page doesn’t have to show DoubleClick ads for this to happen; it just needs to include DoubleClick ad tags, which might load a click tracker or impression pixel instead. The Floodlight Tag will only be collecting pseudonymous data in order to track the success of certain RIMOWA campaigns. It is not going to create a personal profile for you. 

If you want to stop this tool from collecting data, you can opt-out [here](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCjMahctPwEC0bXMNkskZoWjetppeYgOKcN48eHxQVmdi9H6dKi2eArbmNAqwU9zPM3KU2hUKXe1qt8wCgY0IP3P3PcvgtrtFNV0WZIeY6mYpyY-JzY&hl=de).

#### 3.9.2 Facebook Pixel

This website uses the so-called Facebook Pixel (Website Custom Audience Pixel). This pixel collects information about the usage of this website (e.g. products you have looked at) and transmits it to the social network Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union ("Facebook"). Facebook uses this information for advertising and profiling purposes. The Facebook Pixel allows us to target you with individualised advertisement in the Facebook network (e.g. in your Facebook account). If you want to stop this tool from collecting data, you can opt-out [here](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_). You have to be logged in on the Facebook website.

### 3.10 Social plugins

"Social plugins" for a number of social networks have been incorporated into this website. These allow you to recommend content and offerings available on our website to your friends and other people you know. 

Our social plugins are not activated by default. If you choose to activate a social plugin by clicking on it, you can transmit data to the operator of the social network in question. This data can include, in particular, your IP address, browser information and operating system, screen resolution, installed browser plugins such as Adobe Flash Player, where visitors originated from if they followed a link (referrer), the URL of the current page or in-formation on the use of a certain service on this website. 

The processing of your personal data described in this section is necessary for the purpose of the legitimate interests pursued by RIMOWA: We have a legitimate interest in processing our user’s data upon their request if they activate the plugin and request to share information with a social network. The section below provides you with information on the social plugins on this website. You can find further information on the scope and purpose of the collection, processing and use of your (personal) data and, where appropriate, on the data protection settings in the data protection information of the relevant social network 

#### 3.10.1 Facebook plugins

Plugins relating to the social network Facebook, 1601 South California Avenue, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union) ("Facebook") have been integrated into this website. You can recognize them by the Facebook logo or the “Like” button on our page. You can find an overview of the Facebook plugins [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/203587239679209?helpref=related). 

When you visit our website, the plugin establishes a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server. This informs Facebook that you have visited our page using your IP address. 

If you click on the Facebook “like” button while you are logged in to your Facebook account, then you can link the content of our website with your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to allocate the visit to our website to your user account. 

We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by Facebook. You can find further information on the handling of your data in the Facebook Data Policy [here](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php). 

#### 3.10.2 Google+

The "+1” button provided by the Google social network “Google+” and operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, California, 94043 USA (“Google”), a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union, has also been integrated into this website. 

Every time you access a page featuring the “+1” button on our website, the “+1” button prompts the browser you are using to load the visual representation of the “+1” button from the Google server and display it. This informs the Google server of which page of our website you are currently visiting. Google logs your browser history in connection with the display of a “+1” button for a period of up to two weeks for system maintenance and trouble-shooting purposes. Your visit to one of our websites that features a “+1” button is not analysed any further. If you press the “+1” button, Google records information, via your Google profile, on the URL recommended by you, your IP address and other browser-related information so that your “+1” recommendation can be saved and made publicly available. Your “+1” recommendations can be shown as references, together with your profile name and your photo, in Google services, e.g. in search results, or in your Google profile (as a “+1” tab in your Google profile), or in other places on websites and advertisements on the Internet. We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by Google. You can find the Google Privacy Policy [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

#### 3.10.3 Twitter

This website also incorporates Twitter functions that are made available by Twitter, Inc. 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA - a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union - (“Twitter”). Using the Twitter functions (e.g. the “re-tweet” function) links the websites visited by you to your Twitter account and makes this information available to other users. We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by Twit-ter. You can find further information in the Twitter Privacy Policy. You can change your data protection settings in Twitter in your Twitter account settings [here](https://twitter.com/settings). 

#### 3.10.4 YouTube

Plugins relating to the social network YouTube, 901 Cherry Avenue, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA - a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union - ("YouTube") have been integrated into this website. You can recognize them by the YouTube logo on our page. You can find an overview of the YouTube plugins [here](https://de.wordpress.org/plugins/youtube-embed-plus/). We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by YouTube. You can find further information on the handling of your data by YouTube [here](https://www.youtube.com/static?template=privacy_guidelines).   

#### 3.10.5 Weibo

Plugins relating to the social network Weibo, 8/F, QIHAO Plaza, No. 8 Xinyuan S. Road Chaoyang District, Beijing 100027, People’s Republic of China ("Weibo") - a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union - have been integrated into this website. You can recognize them by the Weibo logo on our page. You can find an overview of the Weibo plugins [here](https://wordpress.org/plugins/sina-weibo-plugin-for-wordpress/). We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by Weibo. You can find further information on the handling of your data by Weibo [here](https://www.weibo.com/signup/v5/privacy). 

#### 3.10.6 WeChat

Plugins relating to the social network WeChat - a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union -have been integrated into this website. You can find further information in the [WeChat Privacy Policy](https://www.wechat.com/en/cookies_policy.html). You can recognize them by the WeChat logo on our page. You can find an overview of the WeChat plugins [here](https://blog.grata.co/wechat-plugins/). 

We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by WeChat. You can find further information on the handling of your data [here](http://www.wechat.com/mobile/htdocs/en/privacy_policy.html). 

#### 3.10.7 LinkedIn

Plugins relating to the social network LinkedIn, 1000 West Maude Avenue, Sunnyvale, CA 94085, USA ("LinkedIn") - a territory where the level of protection of privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union -have been integrated into this website. You can recognize them by the LinkedIn logo on our page. You can find an overview of the LinkedIn plugins [here](https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins). 

We would like to point out that, as the website provider, we are not aware of the content of the data transmitted or the manner in which it is used by LinkedIn. You can find further information on the handling of your data by LinkedIn [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy?trk=). 

## 4\. RECIPIENTS OF THE DATA

Your Data shall be processed by RIMOWA (including its affiliated companies). It is not going to be transferred or made accessible to any third party with the exception of (i) possible subcontractors of RIMOWA (e.g., carriers, providers of hosting and maintenance services of the Site, payment and fraud management service providers, web analysis providers etc.), for purely technical and logistical reasons, (ii) with third parties offering tracking technologies or social plugins (e.g. Facebook plugin, Google+, Twitter) as described at 3.9 and 3.10 above, and (iii) in case of a reorganisation of RIMOWA, including total or partial transfer of assets, merger, takeover, de-merger, and in general any reorganisation transaction; and (iv) as otherwise described in this section 4. 

Your Data may be disclosed to affiliated companies of RIMOWA for purposes of management and optimisation of the customer relationship, and, subject to your consent, to send you information about the offers, news and events of RIMOWA and its affiliated companies.

Finally, RIMOWA may disclose your Data to third parties if such disclosure is required by law, by a regulatory provision or by a court ruling, or if this disclosure is necessary to ensure the protection and defence of its rights.

## 5\. TRANSFERS OF DATA ABROAD

We also forward personal data to affiliated companies, third parties or subcontractors who are located outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA") countries, including, among others, territories like the USA where the level of protection of your privacy is not equivalent to the one enjoyed in the European Union. In such cases we ensure prior to the transfer that the transfer is subject to appropriate safeguards (e.g., by self-certification of the recipient under the EU US Privacy Shield (Art. 45 GDPR) or by having agreed upon so-called standard data protection clauses of the European Union with the recipient (Art. 46 GDPR) or where express user consent is given.

In case we forward your personal data to countries outside the EU this has been indicated in this Policy. A copy of the safeguards implemented by RIMOWA as well as an overview of third country recipients may be obtained by sending a request to RIMOWA.

## 6\. RETENTION PERIOD OF YOUR DATA

The Data that is collected and processed under the "Contact" section shall only be kept for the duration of the processing of your request. It shall be deleted thereafter. 

Should you decide to create a customer account, your identification Data shall be kept for as long as your account is active and you do not close it. You may close your account at any time. Your request shall be taken into consideration immediately, or in case of any pending purchase order, as soon as it is performed in full. Should your account remain inactive for three (3) years, RIMOWA shall contact you to find out whether or not you wish to maintain your account. Should you not wish to maintain it, your account shall be closed and your Data (excluding your purchase history, see below) shall be destroyed. The Data concerning your purchase history shall in principle be kept by RIMOWA for a period of time that does not exceed the applicable statutory limitation periods. This Data may however also be viewed from your customer account as long as the latter remains active. Upon closure of your customer account, this Data (i) shall be archived for accounting and evidentiary purposes for the abovementioned statutory limitation periods, or (ii) shall be destroyed if these periods have expired. 

Your bank account Data shall be kept secure for the duration that is needed for the confirmation of your purchase order and its payment and shall then be immediately destroyed. In case of a payment default, your Data shall be kept throughout the duration of the management of the incident, and thereafter for a period of three (3) to five (5) years depending on the seriousness of the incident, unless we are required to keep the data for a longer time under applicable law.

The Data that is used for the purpose of sending you information concerning the offers, news and events of RIMOWA shall be kept for a period of three (3) years as from the date on which it was collected or as from your latest contact with RIMOWA. Upon expiry of this timescale, RIMOWA may get in touch with you to find out whether you wish to continue to receive information about our offers, news and events. Such Data shall be deleted within a maximum of one (1) month following any request on your part to unsubscribe.

IP addresses collected for security purposes will not be stored for longer than 10 days. Finally, the connection logs that are collected, subject to your consent, using cookies and other trackers implemented on our Site, shall be kept in accordance with applicable laws and regulations for a period of time that does not exceed thirteen (13) months. For more details, see our Cookie Policy.

## 7\. YOUR RIGHTS

In accordance with applicable data protection laws and regulations, you have a right to request access to, rectification or erasure of your Data (including Data related to your profiling), or restriction of processing, and to object to said processing including profiling for marketing purposes, as well as the right to data portability. You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

**Right to object to direct marketing**

Additionally, you may at all times object to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes. Please take into account that, due to logistical reasons, there might be an overlap between your objection and the usage of your data within the scope of a campaign which is already running. 

**Right to object to processing based on legitimate interest**

Furthermore, you may have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of personal data concerning you which is based on the legal basis legitimate interests.

Should you oppose the use of your Data for the building up of your client profile; you will no longer benefit from customised offers or services. These rights may be exercised directly at the following address [hello@rimowa.com](mailto:hello@rimowa.com). You may be asked for proof of identity. 

You can also contact us by telephone by calling +49 (221) 956–4170 (calls are subject to no surcharge) from 8am to 8pm, 5 days a week or by regular post by writing to RIMOWA international, Richard-Byrd-Strasse 13, 50829 Cologne, Germany or [hello@rimowa.com](mailto:hello@rimowa.com).

Furthermore, you may request at any time that we stop sending you information about our offers, news and events by using the hypertext link included to that effect in each e-mail that we send you. 

## 8\. CONTACT DETAILS OF THE DATA PROTECTION OFFICER (DPO) AND RIGHT TO LODGE A COMPLAINT WITH A SUPERVISORY AUTHORITY 

Should you have any question about the collection and processing of your Data by RIMOWA, please contact the data protection officer of RIMOWA by sending an e-mail to [dataprotection@rimowa.com](mailto:dataprotection@rimowa.com).

\- BECHTLE Datenschutz Competence Center -

Bechtle GmbH IT-Systemhaus  
Parkstraße 2-8, 47829 Krefeld  
You may also address your complaint to a supervisory authority regarding the way in which RIMOWA collects and processes your Data. The supervisory authority competent for RIMOWA is the Landesbeauftragte für Datenschutz und Informationsfreiheit Nordrhein-Westfalen, Postfach 20 04 44, 40102 Düsseldorf, Deutschland, [www.ldi.nrw.de](https://www.ldi.nrw.de/).

## 9\. COLLECTION OF DATA ON THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES

Links on this website may take you to third-party websites that are not within our sphere of control. As a result, please read the terms and conditions of use and data protection information on these websites to find out more about the collection, pro-cessing and use of (personal) information on these websites. 

## 10\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We may change this Policy from time to time in order to reflect changes in the law and/or our privacy practices. In this case we will inform you accordingly in advance.

## B. Cookie Policy

## RIMOWA COOKIE POLICY JUNE 2018

The website [https://www.rimowa.com](https://www.rimowa.com/) (also the "Site") is operated by RIMOWA international, having its registered office at Richard-Byrd-Str. 13, 50829 Cologne, Germany (“RIMOWA”), in its capacity as data controller for the purposes of applicable data protection laws and regulations.

In order to make our website as user-friendly as possible, we – like many other renowned companies – use “cookies”. 

Cookies are small text files that are sent when visiting an internet page and are stored in a user’s browser. In case the respective internet page is accessed once again, the user’s browser sends back the content of the cookies and, thus, allows for the recognition of the user. Most of the cookies we use are “session cookies” that are deleted when you end your browser session. This Cookie Policy should be read in conjunction with our Privacy Policy, [here](https://www.rimowa.com/de/en/customer-service/privacy-%26-security/privacy-policy.html) and sets out how RIMOWA will use cookies in connection with the Site. Typically cookies do not collect personal data but may be used to create a user profile. In this case, you will be informed about this in the Privacy Policy [here](https://www.rimowa.com/de/en/customer-service/privacy-%26-security/privacy-policy.html).

## 1\. THE TYPES OF COOKIES WE USE AND THEIR PURPOSES

Cookies may be set either by the Site (“first party cookies”) or by third party websites who run content on the website you are looking at (“third party cookies”). 

The cookies used on our website are categorised, as follows:

• Cookies which are “strictly necessary” for the functionality of the website’s platforms. These cookies are essential in order to enable users to move around the website and fulfil express requests from you as a user of the website (e.g., cookies which serve the purpose of identifying or authenticating our users so you do not need to log in again very time you visit the website or cookies that temporarily store certain user entries like shopping cart content or content of an online form). 

• “Functionality” cookies which allow the website to remember choices you make and your preferences for example where you register/sign-up for events, products and/or services or to set the language or the currency.

• “Performance/Analytics” cookies which collect information about how users navigate the website, for example, which pages users access most frequently. They identify how users interact with our website, any errors that occur, which pages are not used often, which pages take a long time to load, which pages users tend to visit and in what order. These cookies do not collect any information which could identify you and are only used to help us improve how our website works and understand what interests our website’s users (e.g., clicked ad banners, visited subpages, search queries asked).

• “Targeting or advertising” cookies used to deliver adverts relevant to an identified machine or other device (not a named or otherwise identifiable person) which are tailored to interests associated with the website activity tied to that machine or device (e.g., clicked ad banners, visited subpages, search queries asked). For example, if a cookie on a third party website recognises that a particular product was purchased from a particular device, that cookie may “talk to” marketing cookies on the website to ensure advertisements about similar products displayed on the website are accessed from that device. These cookies are also used to limit the number of times a user sees an advertisement as well as to help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. They may also remember that the website has been visited from a device and share that information with marketing organisations. The marketing cookies on our website are operated by third parties with our permission. Marketing cookies are used to monitor from which advertising source a user was directed towards our website so that we know whether it is worth us investing in that particular advertising source.

• "Third Party Social Plugin Sharing Cookies" in connection with Social Plugins: Embedding Social Plugins generally has the plugins’ providers store cookies. These cookies allow our users to share information with the respective social network but also allow the network operator to identify the user and store information about the usage of the website by the user in his/her profile. For further information please see our Privacy Policy (at sec. 3.10) [here](https://www.rimowa.com/de/en/customer-service/privacy-%26-security/privacy-policy.html).

## 2\. YOUR CONSENT TO OUR USE OF COOKIES AND HOW TO DELETE COOKIES

We will capture your consent to the use of certain cookies set out in this Policy when you first access the website and if we introduce any new cookies to the website (unless they are strictly necessary cookies). If so, when you first visit the website, a banner will appear asking you to agree to the cookies that we set on the website.

If you reject cookies, we will not set any further cookies on your device, except the “strictly necessary” cookies detailed above (including, unavoidably, a cookie to remember that you don't want any cookies set when you visit the website). You can usually set your browser to warn you when a cookie is being sent or to remove or reject cookies. Each browser is different, so look at your browser ‘Help’ menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings. If you choose to remove or reject cookies, it will affect many features or services on our website.

If you agree to cookies from our website by continuing to use the website OR clicking "OK", we will set cookies on your device. If you wish to delete the cookies we have set on your device, you can do this via your web browser settings. 

## 3\. STORAGE PERIODS

The various cookies used by us have different storage periods, at the end of which your data will no longer be stored. However, cookies implemented on our Site shall be kept in accordance with applicable laws and regulations for a period of time that does not exceed thirteen (13) months. For specific storage periods see table below.

## 4\. COOKIE TABLE

**Purpose**

| 

**Type of cookie**

| 

**First party or third party cookie?**

| 

**Cookie name**

| 

**Name of application**

| 

**Storage period**

| 

**Link to page allowing you to disable the cookie**

| 

**Link to privacy policy of third party provider**  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Session 

| 

First party 

| 

csrftoken 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

Browser session 

| 

/ 

| 

Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Session 

|  | 

csrf_token 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

Browser session 

| 

/ 

| 

Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Session 

|  | 

cookieNoticeShown 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

/ 

| 

/   
  
Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Session 

|  | 

cookieNoticeClosed 

| 

www.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

/ 

| 

/   
  
Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Session 

|  | 

dw 

| 

rimowa.com 

| 

Session 

| 

/ 

| 

Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

|  | 

dw_cookies_accepted 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

/ 

| 

Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

|  | 

weird_get_top_level_domain 

| 

rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

/ 

| 

Javascript Privacy Policy  
  
Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Session 

|  | 

uuid 

| 

.cquotient.com 

| 

Session 

| 

/ 

| 

Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

|  | 

__cq_uuid 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

/ 

| 

Salesforce Privacy Policy  
  
Functional cookie (technical cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

|  | 

__cq_seg 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

/ 

| 

Salesforce Privacy Policy  
  
Analytics (profiling cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

| 

Third party cookie 

| 

_ga 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

| 

Analytics (profiling cookies) 

| 

Permanent 

|  | 

‎_gid 

| 

.[rimowa.com](http://rimowa.com/)

| 

13 months 

| 

| 

Analytics 

| 

Permanent 

| 

Third party cookie 

|  | 

Hotjar 

| 

13 months 

| 

| 

Analytics (profiling cookie)s 

| 

Permanent 

| 

Third party cookie 

| 

_kla_id 

| 

www.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

| 

Analytics (profiling cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

| 

Third party cookie 

| 

_dc_gtm_UA-15884891-2 

| 

.rimowa.com 

| 

13 months 

| 

| 

Third party tracking cookie (profiling cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

| 

Third party cookie 

| 

IDE 

| 

Doubleclick Floodlight Tags 

| 

13 months 

| 

| 

Third party tracking cookie (profiling cookie) 

| 

Permanent 

| 

Third party cookie 

| 

fr 

| 

Facebook Pixel 

| 

13 months 

| 

[Facebook Pixel opt-out](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_=_). You have to be logged in on the Facebook website. 

| 

## 5\. HOW CAN I MANAGE MY COOKIE INSTALLATION PREFERENCES?

In addition to what is stated in this document, you can manage your preferences pertaining to cookies directly on your browser and prevent, for example, third parties from installing them on your device. In addition, through the browser preferences, you can delete previously installed cookies. Please note that by disabling all cookies, the operation of this website may be compromised. You can find more information as to managing cookies in their browsers by going to the following link: [www.youronlinechoices.com](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

You may disable first party technical cookies referred to in the table by clicking on the links or, in the case of third parties technical cookies by clicking on the information notices and the forms for consent of such third party. Notwithstanding, the deactivation of such cookies may compromise the correct surfing and the functionalities of the Site. 

You may disable first party profiling cookie referred to in the table by clicking on the links indicated or, in the case of third parties cookies, by accessing the information notices and the form for consent of such third party. 

## 6\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We may change this Policy from time to time in order to reflect changes in the law and/or our privacy practices. We will update the Policy accordingly and ask you to re-consent to our use of cookies. 

If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact us at:  
RIMOWA international   
Richard-Byrd-Strasse 13  
50829 Cologne, Germany   
Phone: + 49 (221) 956–4170  
Fax: +49 (221) 956–4174  
Email: [hello@rimowa.com](mailto:hello@rimowa.com)  
Or contact the data protection officer of RIMOWA by sending an e-mail to [dataprotection@rimowa.com](mailto:dataprotection@rimowa.com).

\- BECHTLE Datenschutz Competence Center -  
Bechtle GmbH IT-Systemhaus  
Parkstraße 2-8, 47829 Krefeld
